A Guide to the Edward Kramer papers FA1120
Rockefeller Archive Center
Edward Kramer papers
1970-1973, 1976, 1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Kramer, Edward
FA1120
1.8 Cubic Feet 4 legal size document boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Material remains in order as received, with the following series: Series 1: General. Series 2: 1970 Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated to the RAC by Edward Kramer in 2015. The records were ingested as Accession 2015:102.
Scope and Contents
Material primarily pertains to the 1970 Gubernatorial Campaign of Nelson A. Rockefeller and the Environmental Bond Coalition. Records include travel arrangements, schedules, itineraries.
Biographical / Historical
Edward Kramer served as Special Advanceman for the 1970 Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign.
- General, 1
  - Transportation Board Issue, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Environmental Bond Issue and Bike Ride, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Environmental Bond Issue and Bike Ride, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Bond Issue and Bike Ride - Photos, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Transportation Bond Issue, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Governor's Conference, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New York State Environmental Conservation T-shirt and Apron - Realia, 1972; 2015:102:001 (Box 2015:102:001)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from scholarly access - pending stabilization.
    Separated Materials
    Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, realia, and still image material) have been separated from the file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - New York State Environmental Conservation Apron - Realia, 1972; 2015:102:002 (Box 2015:102:002)
  - Transportation Bond Issue, Legislator Radio Spots Senators and Assemblyman - Moving Image, 2015:102:003 (Box 2015:102:003)
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - Balloons - Realia, 2015:102:004 (Box 2015:102:004)
  - Pins - Realia, 2015:102:005 - 2015:102:009 (Box 2015:102:005-2015:102:009)
  - R-Cap -Realia, 2015:102:010 (Box 2015:102:010)
  - Rocky's Team Shirt -Realia, 2015:102:011 (Box 2015:102:011)
  - New York State Environmental Conservation T-Shirt - Realia, 2015:102:012 (Box 2015:102:012)
  - The Nelson A. Rockefeller Public Service Award Dinner, Waldorf-Astoria, NYC, 1988 June 16 (Box 4, Folder 86)
- 1970 Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign, 2
  - Family Day Picnic - Staten Island, 1970 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Construction start Ceremony amd West Farms Housing Development, 1970 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Twin Parks Groundbreaking, 1970 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Polish Reception, 1970 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Office and Prof. Employees Internatonal, 1970 October 30 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - New York City "Man of the Year" (p.m) Community Mayors, 1970 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Legion Testimonial Dinner Dance, 1970 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Annual Pulaski Day Parade, 1970 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Local 144 Drop-In, 1970 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Brooklyn Storefront Rally and Walking Tour, 1970 October 7-9 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Richmond County Rep. Comm. Dinner, 1970 October (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Erie and New York Counties, 1970 October 12 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Columbus Day Parade, 1970 October 12 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Long Island Federation of Labor, 1970 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Uniformed Sanitation Mens Union, 1970 October 15 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Italian Mayors Breakfast Drop in, 1970 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hispanic Transit Workers Dance, 1970 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Services Employees Joint Council Reception, 1970 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bronx Walking Tour, 1970 October 17 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - New Cadet Headquarters Groundbreaking, 1970 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - The Shormrim Society of N.Y.C. Police Department, 1970 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - U.N. Reception, 1970 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Williamsburg Rabbis Meeting, 1970 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Headquarters Visit and Queens Walking Tour, 1970 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 55th Street Rally, 1970 October 20 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Pace College, 1970 October 21 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Midtown rally- Storefront Opening, 1970 October 26 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Garment Center Rally, 1970 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Electrical Welfare Club, Waldorf Astoria, NYC, 1970 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Steinway Street Walking Tour, 1970 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - La Marquita Tour- Cancelled, 1970 October 26 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Queens Rally, 1970 October 28 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Wall St. Rally, 1970 October 27 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Queens Walking Tour, 1970 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Nassau County Rally, 1970 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Events, 1970 October 30-November 1 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Erie, Albany, Westchester, 1970 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Candidates Breakfast, Waldorf-Astoria, NYC, 1970 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Narcotics Tour, 1970 August 3 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Student Presidents Meeting, 1970 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Beaches, Reis Park, 1970 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Associates of the Rockefeller Team Breakfast, 1970 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - National March on Drugs Corps, 1970 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - College Editors Meeting, 1970 August 18 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Campaign Headquarters Openings, 1970 August 18 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Brooklyn Walking Tour, 1970 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Teamsters Convention, Concord Hotel, 1970 August 19 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Ticonderoga, NY, 1970 August 25 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Ticonderoga, NY Photos - Still Image, 2015:102:013 (Box 2015:102:013)
  - Miss Universe Day, 1970 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - A.F.L-C.I.O. Convention, Concord Hotel, 1970 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Catskills Tour, 1970 September 6 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Walking Tour, Bronx Shopping Center - Cancelled, 1970 September 12 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - San Gennero Festival, 1970 September 11 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Press Conference, Commodore Hotel, 1970 September 14 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Ethnic Press Reception - Dinner, Monks Inn, 1970 September 15 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Brooklyn Retarded Hostel Dedication, 1970 September 16 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Women's Finance Div. of the Republican State Committee Luncheon, 1970 September 18 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - New York City Walking Tour, 1970 September 19 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Steuban Day Parade, 1970 September 19 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - 90th Anniv. Ceremonies, Salvation Army - Cancelled, 1970 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Staten Island Headquarters Opening, 1970 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - World Trade Center, 1970 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Touchdown Club, 1970 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Old Age Conference, 1970 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Uniformed Fire Officers Association, 1970 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Testimonial Dinner - John Marchi, 1970 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Affiliated Young Democrats, Inc., 1970 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Barbers Association, 1970 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - International Union of Operating Engineers, 1970 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Propeller Club Luncheon, 1970 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Arts Committee Reception, 1970 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Beth Israel Drop In, 1970 September 25 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Temple Beth - EL Dedication Great Neck, NY, 1970 September 25 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 1970 Rockefeller Campaign (Box 4, Folder 83-84)
    - M.O.D. Corps, March on Drugs pin - Realia, 2015:102:014 (Box 2015:102:014)
    - Pin - Realia, 2015:102:015 (Box 2015:102:015)
    - Labor Likes Rocky pin- Realia, 2015:102:016 (Box 2015:102:016)
      Restricted from scholarly accces - pending stabilization.
    - Untitled photos - Still Image, 2015:102:017 (Box 2015:102:017)
    - Pens - Realia, 2015:102:018 - 2015:102:019 (Box 2015:102:018-2015:102:019)
    - glad-hamp records Inc. Lionel Hampton and his Rocke-Fellers - Audio, 2015:102:020 (Box 2015:102:020)
      • Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
    - Dried Balloon - Realia, 2015:102:026 (Box 2015:102:026)
  - Events, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Ford Dole pin - Realia, 2015:102:021 (Box 2015:102:021)
  - Italians love Ford pin - Realia, 2015:102:022 (Box 2015:102:022)
  - G pin - Realia, 2015:102:023 (Box 2015:102:023)
  - Oversize - Ephemera, 2015:102:024 (Box 2015:102:024)
  - Pen - Realia, 2015:102:025 (Box 2015:102:025)